<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

	<properties>
		<title>Creating a Java/Eclipse Build Environment</title>
	</properties>

	<body>
	<p>You can either use Bluefin start up kit or setup the development environment by yourself.
	Follow the instructions from the below section depending on your choice.</p>
		<section name="Use Bluefin Startup Kit">
		A quick way to have the required development environment and start working on bluefin is to 
		use the Bluefin Startup Kit : <a href="https://confluence.paypal.com/cnfl/display/QI/Bluefin+Startup+Kit">https://confluence.paypal.com/cnfl/display/QI/Bluefin+Startup+Kit</a>
		</section>
		<section name="Creating a Java and Eclipse build environment from scratch by yourself">
		    <p>
		      Follow these instructions for setting up Eclipse and dependent plugins by downloading each component 
		      from the Internet.
		    </p>
		    
			<subsection name="Download and install both Java and Eclipse">
				<ul>
					<li>
						First, download Java (We'd recommend downloading the JDK, any
						version 5 and up will do), here's a link to the latest Java SE downloads:
						<a href="http://java.sun.com/javase/downloads/index.jsp">
							http://java.sun.com/javase/downloads/index.jsp</a>
						(If you already have a development kit
						installed of version 5 or higher, you can skip this step).
						<ul>
							<li>
								<b>NOTE</b>: We recommend installing the JDK to the root directory,
								i.e. C:\. Problems come up when defaulting to Program Files.
							</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li>
						Download Eclipse (I'd recommend the Eclipse IDE for Java
						Developers):
						<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/">http://www.eclipse.org/</a>
						<ul>
							<li>
								<b>NOTE</b>: We highly recommend installing Eclipse to the root directory,
								i.e. C:\. Problems come up when defaulting to Program Files.
							</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li>
						Once you've installed Java, and unzipped Eclipse, start up Eclipse
					</li>
				</ul>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Install Eclipse plugins">
				<p>
					Installing Eclipse plugins can be done through the Eclipse toolbar,
                    Help->Software Updates. For Eclipse
                    3.3+ it's under the Available Software tab, and click Add Site...
                    button to add the URL.
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>
						<i>Install the Maven Eclipse plugin</i>
						<ul>
							<li>
								The information on the m2eclipse plugin can be found here:
								<a href="http://m2eclipse.codehaus.org/">http://m2eclipse.codehaus.org/</a>
							</li>
							<li>
								The m2eclipse page should have the update URL that you need to
								supply, please check that page
								for the needed info.
                            </li>
							<li>
								As of recently, there has been a problem with the normal build, if
								you are experiencing problems,
								try the developer build link.
                            </li>
							<li>
								You only need to install 2 things, from the Maven Integration
								branch: Maven Embedder and Maven Integration for Eclipse.
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                We also recommend downloading and installing the commandline version of 
                                Maven which is available at <a href="http://maven.apache.org/download.html">
                                http://maven.apache.org/download.html</a>. 
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                        <b>Note:</b> Currently, we recommend version 2.2.1. Furthermore,
                                        if you install the commandline version of Maven we also recommend
                                        you configure the Maven Eclipse plugin to use this version. This is 
                                        accomplished via the Eclipe toolbar, Windows->Preferences->Maven->Installations. 
                                        Once here, select "Add" and point to your commandline installation. 
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
						</ul>
					</li>
                    <li>
                        <i>Install the TestNG plugin</i>
                        <ul>
                            <li>
                                Instructions can be found here:
                                <a href="http://testng.org/doc/eclipse.html">http://testng.org/doc/eclipse.html</a>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>					
                    <li>
						<i>Install the EGit plugin</i>
						<ul>
							<li>
								Instructions can be found here:
								<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/egit/">http://www.eclipse.org/egit/</a>
							</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
				</ul>
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>