<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

	<properties>
		<title>Maven Archetype</title>
	</properties>

	<body>
		<p>
			Here's instructions on how to use the Bluefin Maven Archetype to setup your
			project:
        </p>
		<p>
			<b>
				If you haven't done so already, be sure to first setup the
				<a href="createBluefinDevEnv.html">
					Java and Eclipse build environment</a>
			</b>
		</p>
		<p>
			A
			<a
				href="http://maven.apache.org/guides/introduction/introduction-to-archetypes.html">Maven Archetype</a>
			,
			acts like a Wizard that steps you through the process of setting up a
			Java project. People create an archetype
			to bundle all the necessary setup into one command, so instead of
			having to create and modify all the files,
			the archetype does it for you.
		</p>
		<p>
			There are two ways of using the Maven Archetype. The Eclipse Maven
			plugin (m2) allows you to step through
			the process within Eclipse, but it has been known to have issues. We
			recommend you try to use the Eclipse
			Maven plugin first, and if you experience problems, try the manual way via
			the command line. The command line
			requires that you install
			<a href="http://maven.apache.org/download.html">Maven</a>
			.
		</p>
		<section name="Using the Maven Archetype via Eclipse">
			<p>
				Start with the Eclipse New Project Wizard.
            </p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					Click File -> New -> Project..., and select Maven -> Maven Project,
					click Next.
                </li>
				<li>
					Make sure the "Create a simple project (skip archetype selection) is
					deselected, leave all
					the other settings default, and click Next.
                </li>
				<li>
					Make sure the "Catalog" option is "Nexus Indexer," and click the "Add
					Archetype..." button.
                </li>
				<li>
					Enter in the following information:
					<ul>
						<li>
							Archetype Group Id: com.paypal.test.bluefin
                        </li>
						<li>
							Archetype Artifact Id: BluefinArchetype
                        </li>
						<li>
							Archetype Version: 0.5.0
                        </li>
						<li>
							Archetype Repository:
							http://nexus.paypal.com/nexus/content/groups/public-all/
                        </li>
					</ul>
				</li>
				<li>
					Click OK
                </li>
				<li>
					Select the newly listed "BluefinArchetype" from the available list of
					archetypes, and click Next
                </li>
				<li>
					Enter in your project specific information:
					<ul>
						<li>
							Group Id: com.paypal.test.&lt;vertical&gt; (where &lt;vertical&gt; is
							your vertical, i.e. risk, merchant, etc)
                        </li>
						<li>
							Artifact Id: (enter in the name of your project, maybe SendMoneyTests, or
							whatever you are working on)
                        </li>
						<li>
							Version: (you can leave the default or choose something else)
                        </li>
						<li>
							Package: com.paypal.test.&lt;vertical&gt; (where &lt;vertical&gt; is your
							vertical, i.e. risk, merchant, etc)
                        </li>
					</ul>
				</li>
				<li>
					Click Finish
                </li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				The Maven Archetype will now create your project for you, setting up
				all the specifics necessary to allow you to
				use the Jaws code and run your tests. The jawsConfig.xml file is not
				configured (you will need to
				configure the variables needed). If you have any problems, please try the
				command line as described in the next section.
            </p>
		</section>
		<section name="Using the Maven Archetype via the command line">
			<p>
				To use the command line, you must first download and install
				<a href="http://maven.apache.org/download.html">Maven</a>
				.
				Once you have done so, open a command prompt, change directories to the
				directory you want your project created in
				(most likely your Eclipse workspace), and run:
			</p>
			<code>
				mvn archetype:generate -B -DartifactId=MyBluefinTests
				-Dversion=1.0.0-SNAPSHOT -DgroupId=com.paypal.test
				-DarchetypeGroupId=com.paypal.test.bluefin
				-DarchetypeArtifactId=Bluefin-Archetype -DarchetypeVersion=0.5.0
				-DarchetypeRepository=http://nexus.paypal.com/nexus/content/groups/public-all
			</code>
			<p>
				It may download some things to get the environment setup, then begin
				to prompt you for your project specific information.
				Enter in the following for each prompt:
            </p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					groupId: com.paypal.test.&lt;vertical&gt; (where &lt;vertical&gt; is your
					vertical, i.e. risk, merchant, etc)
                </li>
				<li>
					artifactId: (enter in the name of your project, maybe SendMoneyTests, or
					whatever you are working on)
                </li>
				<li>
					version: (you can leave the default or choose something else)
                </li>
				<li>
					package: com.paypal.test.&lt;vertical&gt; (where &lt;vertical&gt; is your
					vertical, i.e. risk, merchant, etc)
                </li>
			</ul>
			<p>
                Confirm the properties for the configuration, and hit enter.  The Maven Archetype will now create your project for you, 
                setting up all the specifics necessary to allow you to use the Bluefin code and run your tests.  This will create a project in c:\BluefinProjects\MyBluefinTests directory. 
                Now go into the directory by typing
                <code>cd c:\BluefinProjects\MyBluefinTests</code>
                Now run the following command.
                <code>mvn dependency:resolve</code>
                The next step is importing this project into Eclipse:
            </p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					From within Eclipse, select File -> Import..., General -> Existing
					Projects into Workspace.
                </li>
				<li>
					Click "Select root directory" and browse to find your project in the
					filesystem where you created it.
                </li>
				<li>
					Select the project, and click OK.
                </li>
				<li>
					Make sure the project is checked in the Projects panel, and click
					Finish.
                </li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				Eclipse will now import the project, and you should see it appear in the
				Package Explorer. The
				jawsConfig.xml file is not configured (you will need to configure the variables
				needed).
            </p>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>